I believe that
incorrect
you over what true a fish
it is during my life many times I
had I want to be more efficient and I've
taken different actions and I've taken
different decisions trying to be more
efficient but if I view my life
I think that many of those decisions and
actions have been really
counterproductive and I can see similar
patterns in the world companies
organizations individuals or even
countries we view efficient see in a way
which I believe can be extremely country
productive
even if we feel or we believe that we
are becoming more efficient
we are in fact decreasing efficiency and
i'll try to explain why
imagine that this cute little guy was
your son
let's call me mean he's 10 years old
he's full of energy
he has a lot of different interests is a
popular guy he have different hobbies
and their facility little crazy one
he's your son then one day you get the
phone call from his teacher saying we
are worried about the Miller we can see
that he has severe concentration
problems and he cannot really
participate in the regular class he
asked concentration problems and we have
been discussing this and we have a
hypothesis that he might have ADHD ADHD
what is that
attention deficit hyperactivity disorder
that means that a person have difficult
to focus here she's impulsive and has
full of hyper-energy that's ADHD
can you imagine if you got that message
how would you react react as a parent
maybe you would agree that well let's
make an investigation because ADHD is
considered to be a handicap
so then working question what happens
when you do an ADHD investigation
well there are seven different steps the
first step is that the parents
they meet with the professionals and
discuss the situation after that step
then you have a chat with the child and
get his or her perspective
after that you do a functional I'm
investigation to see what is working
what's not working
after that you do a psychological
investigation and then after that you go
to the medical investigation in the
cellar psychological investigation
you see how they react if they cannot if
they can concentrate in the medical
investigation
you see how they react in different
medicines
then you can compile all the information
from the different tests and you do a
lot of different questionnaires and then
you can settle
he has ADHD or not so it looks fairly
effective seven different steps
the problem is this is not the case in
the real war
it doesn't look like this fast sequence
of seven different steps rather it looks
like this
there's some green part where they in
fact do the investigation but there's a
lot of red part as well where we wait
because the way we organize Oregon
organizations and companies today is in
two different islands different
functions where each function has one
certain responsibilities
so it's like taking a boat to different
islands that when you go to Thailand you
travel to all these different islands
and that's exactly how an ADHD
investigation look like and then one can
question if you are traveling to these
seven different islands
how long does it take well this is a
real example from the southern part of
Sweden and it took in fact for months
and then one can question is that
efficient
what would you say if it was your kid
would it be efficient to wait for four
months
well if we look at this picture we can
compare the green part with a red part
and then maybe we could have a
hypothesis
maybe it's like twenty percent value
adding time and the rest
eighty percent this is a non
value-adding time
that's not the case the real case is
this
if we come if we
combine all 17 or the seven steps will
have 17 hours and contrast that to four
months that is 2880 hours so that means
that our level of efficiency is
zero-point-six percent during 99.4
percent
we are out in the ocean and no one
really cares about us when we're up on
an island then we get full attention
full attention of the doctors they're
fantastic
but when we are in the middle of two
different islands no one really takes
carols
the problem however is that we cannot
get this picture on a regular basis we
don't see the big picture rather our
unit of analysis are only these
different islands and we don't really
analyze them together we analyzed
separately
this is what it looks like from the
company or organizations perspective but
the real problem if we take a customer
or patience or citizens perspective this
is what it looks like
ok email might have ADHD what is
happening then all of a sudden while
it's the first step we have to go there
and use you go there and then is the
next step all IE to chat with the kid
and then it's a functional investigation
and then it's a psychological
investigation and then all of a sudden
well I mean the medical investigation is
tomorrow but we don't have times we have
to reschedule and reschedule
and then the third time yes we needed
medical investigation and then we gather
all information and then all of the
sudden we can settle this is the case
but the problem is we don't see the big
picture because we are traveling to
different islands & each island they
have like attempt over it when you
inside there on the island then it's
fantastic to be there and one can
question is this okay
we can recognize this with health care
within companies and organization even
in the integration process of new Suites
we are developing organizations and
companies that are considered to be
different islands & each island have
different responsibilities
some years ago it was a fantastic man
his name is understood value
he was working with ADHD investigations
at school and university hospital and he
said this is not okay
it's about our children we have to think
in a completely different way so he
gathered all the personnel working on
the seven different islands is that we
need to develop a new way of working
so the question he said what is a good
ADHD investigation everyone had to come
up with their perspective and they said
well it's about seven steps seven
different step seven different islands
and then he said but ok
you have seven different step how can we
develop a way of working where we're
working one team instead of seven
different teams one team where we really
take a parent's perspective in a child's
perspective
so we can deliver a good ADHD
investigation how can we do that where
we have a common goal
where we first deliver quality we want
to make a good investigation but we also
want to deliver speed four months is not
ok we want to do it faster than the sat
down and talked what is our best way of
working
if we are going to work together seven
different steps and they could do
decrease and decrease and decrease and
over time everyone could start to see
the big picture
everyone was not only an island they
said we are one island or one efficient
ocean with different responsibilities
but we have the same goal
so with visualization and continuous
meeting they could control the
investigation process and in fact they
could do to decrease throughput I'm down
to three weeks
so four months down to three weeks and
then one can question how do you do that
well it's fairly simple three weeks
instead of four months they had numerous
positive effects on the organization
first of all it was faster but then they
recognize it's so much easier to handle
this
why because we only have to take care of
five children at the same time
when it takes three weeks when takes
four months we have to handle 35 cases
at the same time think about if you're
at all haha if you were to answer your
emails once a week
how many unanswered emails would you
have in your computer if you were to
answer two times a day you would have
much less little slower that's
mathematical laws which can explain that
so if we go from four months down to
three weeks we go from 35 cases down to
five cases then it was a very creative
secretary said well if it's only five
kids let's take a picture of them we put
them up on the wall and put the names on
them and then we meet in front of this
wall every day so we can make sure that
we control control the progress
this is what looked like this is just
effective picture that approximately
five different kids and a standardized
process in three weeks three steps first
week three steps second week and one
step
the third week and what they did was
that they gather in front of this board
everyone is that have we done step 1 yes
who were around step - yes
have we done step 3 yes good we are on
track after first week and we don't step
for us step 5 yes
step 6 no we haven't gotten their
question area why
and then they could put in extra
resources to handle that case
so in order to be able to secure that
this in fact happened
they can control the progress so that
perfect progress controlled by seeing
the big picture
so there are a lot of positive effects
first of all it was some faster
second of all they could increase and
have stable quality which in turn
delivered a great experience for the
parents
furthermore this reduce the stress of
the personnel and which in turn made the
personal really really proud
but the most interesting part here is
that it increased productivity more than
a hundred percent and what I think is
interesting here is how is this possible
we have a win win win win win win
situation everyone is better
and if we look into micro economic
theory this is not possible we talk
about trade-offs
I mean we cannot deliver high quality at
the same time as low-cost it's
impossible
and so for instance if we have a five
star hotel then we can be good in high
quality but we want delivering in terms
of low-cost or we have a budget hotel we
are good in low-cost but we won't be
delivering high quality and there's we
can have a five star force star three
trials top just the different type of
all of customer needs
but this case here we were beating the
trade of we were increasing quality at
the same time as lowering the costs
increasing productivity and what I think
is a really interesting is the question
how and that's why I want to talk about
efficiency because if we look into
systems today we define efficiency from
a resource perspective we define
efficiency from a functional perspective
it's like we take an organization here's
the customer need and we kept the needs
of the customer up and we say your this
is your responsibility this is your
responsibility and this is your
responsibility
and if I were the president I need KP is
to make sure that everyone delivers
so we measure efficiency on an island
level with this is what we called
resource efficiency
so one can say that if this was a doctor
how much time available
does the doctor have and how much value
can she or he he deliver doing at that
time
and this is what we call the resource
efficiency we try to measure of value
from a certain function or a resource
now the type of perspective that is to
put focus on the patient in this case
it's like putting up a field camera
think if we had a GoPro and we could put
it on email shoulder and press record
once the need was identified until the
need was fulfilled then we would have a
40 or four months long movie
I would tell you that 44 months long
movie
it wouldn't be an action movie we know
that there's only 0.6% that's a
action imagine that you went to a cinema
sitting down waiting and it's only one
minute after two hours that is action
you would leave in a couple of minutes
because here we have competitive
pressures we don't have that especially
not in the public sector we just have to
wait
so when it comes to phone efficiency
then we measure efficiency how well can
we fulfill the need of a customer
totally friends so we have two forms of
efficiencies either we drive have
resource efficiency making people work
more utilize people's competence or we
drive low efficiency meaning that we
feel the need our customers and of
course it's not about either or
we want to reach the star but the
question is if we want to reach star
which of these two forms how to
prioritize first we can compare them
with each other web flow efficiency and
resource efficiency
he resource efficiency we focus on the
resources
the bad thing is that will have long
loop of time because all the islands our
business so they will be accused of
waiting times in front of each Island
the good thing is that we have high
capacity utilization efficiency
here we have focus on the need
instead we focus on how fast can we
fulfill the need but the bad thing is
that we have low capacity utilization
which one of these forms
shall we take low efficiency great from
a customer perspective resource
efficiency great from the economies of
scale perspective but we research can
see is that we shall always always
always drive so efficiency
why I'll think about it what kind of
indirect effects with these two forms
have on our organization
if we fell over focus on resource
efficiency
then we will develop efficient islands
where each Island do not see the big
picture
they only focus on what they are
supposed to be doing and after a while
they develop a subculture sub-culture
which after a while it get a king or
queen saying this is my eye
and don't come here and disturb our way
of working and when we have these kings
and queens on the different islands
what happens then well everyone are
doing a fantastic job
but if you look from a customer
perspective how much of the total time
do we really take care of the customer
well we have a king or a queen taking
care of the customer during
zero-point-six percent of the total time
during 99 perfect . four percent of the
time in this case no one takes care
about the patient or the customer
because they have done their part of the
work
so if we drive resource efficiency we
will go to situation where we have 0 % %
time where we care about the customer
but the indirect effects of low
efficiency is that we go towards full
focus on customer satisfaction or
customer focus and that's drives
effectiveness
we're doing the right thing here drives
ineffectiveness we're doing the wrong
thing because we're making decision from
an island perspective
so what happens here what would you do
if it was your son
email well you would probably sit there
and after a while when you feel that
you've been waiting enough you will
start a call
that's a new need because you're upset
and the doctor have to take care of you
and I can promise you if it was your son
you wouldn't be so nice to the doctors
is that have been waiting now for three
weeks
what is happening then you have to take
care of that
so that's a new need so the organization
develops new needs when we don't focus
on the flow and that's what we call the
efficiency paradox
when we don't see the big picture we
will become ineffective
we cannot see the big picture we make in
correct decisions we develop new needs
and organization will become an engine
of waste and errors
so if we look at this what happened
really
with ADHD example well it took first
four months then they too good
they could in decrease through time what
happens with a number of cases from 35
down to five which is easier is just
want to handle 35 balls or five balls
it's so much easier to handle but those
are the indirect effects that we do not
measure when we measure island
efficiency because that can only be
measured on a system level
so number of cases decreases number of
handled it decreases number of restarts
decrease its complexity decreases and so
much easier
and that's the kind of situation we want
to be here
we need to take care of things that do
not add any value at all but when we can
have over capacity to always make sure
that we have efficient processes then we
don't have delivered true value from a
systems perspective and from a customer
perspective so prioritizing flow
efficiency drives effectiveness we do
the right thing
so my question to you is where do you
put up your camera on your employees or
on your customers
the city sense for your patience
good luck
yeah